Guide to the Peter E. Palmquist Collection of Photography and Photographic Formats
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Printed Material, circa 1846-1994; Series II; 1.9; (17 boxes)
  - Printed Material about Photographic Formats
    - Stereoscopic Photography Literature
      - Dexter, Lorraine. "A Vanished America in Stereo." American Heritage. 12.1 (1960): 113-128., 1960 December (Box 36, Folder 140)
      - Diapocolor. Catalogue of Stereofilms (Box 36, Folder 141)
      - Dickson, Paul. "America in Three-Dimensions." Americana. 3.1 (1975): 2-7., 1975 March (Box 36, Folder 142)
      - Elsinga, H. "Fotograferen in 3-D", 1983 (Box 36, Folder 143)
      - Etter, Roberta B. Stereoscopic Mail Auction, 1985 (Box 36, Folder 144)
      - Ewing, Upton C. "New Development in Stereo." Minicam. (1944): 14., 1944 November-December (Box 36, Folder 145)
      - The Exploratorium. 3-D Promotional materials (Box 36, Folder 146)
      - GAF. Advertisements and instructions (Box 36, Folder 147)
      - Graflex Stereo Graphic. Instruction booklet (Box 36, Folder 148)
      - Grosscup, Jeffrey P. "William H. Illingworth: Stereoscopic Eye on the Frontier West.", 1975 (Box 36, Folder 149)
      - Holex Co. Whole Holography catalogue, 1977 (Box 36, Folder 150)
      - Hoone, Jeffrey. "Jim Pomeroy: Stereo Views." Brochure for the Robert B. Menschel Photography Gallery, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 151)
      - "Illustrated Stereoscopic Sketches." (Box 36, Folder 152)
      - International Stereoscopic Union. Directory, 1982 (Box 36, Folder 153)
      - International Stereoscopic Union. Promotional material (Box 36, Folder 154)
      - Kaiser, Julius B. "Stereo: New Life for an Old Art." Modern Photography. 15.7 (1951): 42-45, 92., 1951 July (Box 36, Folder 155)
      - Keystone View Company. Advertisement (Box 36, Folder 156)
      - Knuchel, Hans. "Reise Ins Land Der 3-Dimension.", 1983 (Box 36, Folder 157)
      - Kodak. "Picture it in Stereo." Instructional booklet, 1955 (Box 36, Folder 158)
      - Kodak Stereo Camera. Advertisement (Box 36, Folder 159)
      - Kodak Stereo Camera. Instruction booklet (Box 36, Folder 160)
      - Kodaslide Stereo Viewer. Instructions (Box 36, Folder 161)
      - Krause, Earl E. "Three-Dimensional Projection", 1955 (Box 36, Folder 162)
      - LOOK. Xograph samples, 1965 (Box 36, Folder 163)
      - Mallan, Lloyd. "Can You See the Moon in 3-D?" Popular Photography. (1965): 52-59., 1965 September (Box 36, Folder 164)
      - "Mammoth Cave in Third Dimension", 1935 (Box 36, Folder 165)
      - Mattey, A. Catalogue of Stereoscope Accessories, as well as a letter to T.V. Wilkerson, 1962 October (Box 36, Folder 166)
      - McClellan, Claire T. "Grandpa's TV - The Stereoscope!" The Western Collector. 8.5 (1970): 8-12., 1970 May (Box 36, Folder 167)
      - McIntyre, Robert L. "Is Stereo Really Dead?" Popular Photography. 36.94 (1960): 79-80, 139., 1960 April (Box 36, Folder 168)
      - McIntyre, Robert L. "Stereo Today." Photography Magazine. (1952): 46-54., 1952 December (Box 36, Folder 169)
      - Mohawk Rubber Company. "The School Children of America are Invited to Take a Trip with Mohawk", 1930 (Box 36, Folder 170)
      - Museum of Holography. "Future Sight: Innovation in Art Holography.", 1987 (Box 36, Folder 171)
      - National Stereoscopic Association. Button from a convention, 1993 (Box 36, Folder 172)
      - National Stereoscopic Association. Foundational materials, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 173)
      - National Stereoscopic Association. Program for 3-D Festival, 1995 (Box 36, Folder 174)
      - Paper Optics. "History in Three Dimensions." Promotional material, 1993 August 1 (Box 36, Folder 175)
      - The Photo Miniature. Reprint of issue on stereoscopic photography, 1909 February (Box 36, Folder 176)
      - Photographic Society of America. List of services (Box 36, Folder 177)
      - Piper, Charles. "The Technical Page", 1989 January (Box 36, Folder 178)
      - Postcards and other promotional materials (Box 36, Folder 179)
      - Poster, Mr. "Modern Stereo Equipment.", 1980 (Box 36, Folder 180)
      - Potomac Society of Stereo Photographers. Directory, 1975 May (Box 36, Folder 181)
      - Powell, Jess. "The Kodak: A Repairman's View.", 1988 (Box 36, Folder 182)
      - Powell, Jess. "The Realist: A Repairman's View.", 1988 (Box 36, Folder 183)
      - Reel 3-D Enterprise. 3-D Catalogue, 1994 (Box 36, Folder 184)
      - Revere Stereo 33 Camera. Instruction Manual (Box 36, Folder 185)
      - Richardson, R.W. "We pretty much specialize in stereo photography..." (Box 36, Folder 186)
      - Robins Industries Corp. Advertisement and correspondence with T.V. Wilkerson, 1962-1963 (Box 36, Folder 187)
      - Ryder, Richard C. "America Through the Stereoscope." American History Illustrated. 18.2 (1983): 8-17., 1983 April (Box 36, Folder 188)
      - Sawyers, Inc. Advertisements and instructions (Box 36, Folder 189)
      - Sawyers, Inc. Letter to T.V. Wilkerson, 1962 January 11 (Box 36, Folder 190)
      - "Seeing 3-D Without Glasses." San Francisco Chronicle, 1993 June (Box 36, Folder 191)
      - Stereo Classics Studio. "The Story of the Stereoscope", 1978 (Box 36, Folder 192)
      - Stereogram, 1994 March (Box 36, Folder 193)
      - Stereo-Magniscope. Advertisement and correspondence with T.V. Wilkerson, 1962 March-April (Box 36, Folder 194)
      - Stereo-Mania. Catalogue (Box 36, Folder 195)
      - The Stereo Realist. Advertisement (Box 36, Folder 196)
      - Stereo-Realist Camera. Instruction books (Box 36, Folder 197)
      - Stereoscopic 3-D Bulletin, 1985 September (Box 36, Folder 198)
        In German and French
      - "Stereoscopic Film Viewer Shows Scenes in Color." Popular Science. 136.6 (1940): 114., 1940 June (Box 36, Folder 199)
      - Stereoscopic Society of America. Membership information (Box 36, Folder 200)
      - "Stereoscopic X-Ray Pictures." The Literary Digest. 44.19 (1912): 984., 1912 May (Box 36, Folder 201)
      - Stereo View Club. Correspondence with T.V. Wilkerson and invoices, 1966 April-August (Box 36, Folder 202)
      - Stereo View Club. Instructional booklets (Box 36, Folder 203)
      - Stereo View Club. Membership materials (Box 36, Folder 204)
      - Stereo View Club. Newsletters, 1964 June-1966 March (Box 36, Folder 205)
      - Symons, K.C.M. "Stereoscopic Cameras.", 1978 (Box 36, Folder 206)
      - Talisman Press. Catalogue of stereoscopic views: "California and the West.", 1983 November (Box 36, Folder 207)
      - Taylor-Merchant Corp. Correspondence with T.V. Wilkerson and literature on stereos. (Box 36, Folder 208)
      - Tru-Vue. Advertisements and film reel lists (Box 36, Folder 209)
      - Tydings, Kenneth. "Revere 33 Stereo Guide.", 1953 (Box 36, Folder 210)
      - Underwood & Underwood. 3-D pages from stereographs (Box 37, Folder 211)
      - Underwood & Underwood. Advertisements (Box 37, Folder 212)
      - Underwood & Underwood. "Egypt and its Wonders Through the Perfecscope", 1897 (Box 37, Folder 213)
      - University of Alaska Museum. "Double Vision: Alaska through the Stereoscope", 1985 (Box 37, Folder 214)
      - View-Master. Advertisements (Box 37, Folder 215)
      - View-Master. Catalogues of Stereoscopic Pictures, 1947 February (Box 37, Folder 216)
      - View-Master. Operating Instructions (Box 37, Folder 217)
      - View-Master. Packet List (Box 37, Folder 218)
      - View-Master. "Three-Dimensional Photography.", 1952 (Box 37, Folder 219)
      - Waack, Fritz G. "Stereo Photography", 1985 (Box 37, Folder 220)
      - Wanless, Harold R. "Aerial Stereo Photographs", 1973 (Box 37, Folder 221)
      - White, Stan. "Beyond the Third Dimension", 1987 (Box 37, Folder 222)
        Signed by the author
      - Wild Card. 3-D Cards with glasses, Yosemite National Park., 1987 (Box 37, Folder 223)
      - Oversize
        - Anaglyph 3D and Polarized 3D glasses (Box 38 (Oversize), Folder 224)
        - GAF Corporation, View-Master order form (Box 38 (Oversize), Folder 225)
        - Lapham, Lewis H. "The Feely is Here," Saturday Evening Post, 1964 April 18 (Box 38 (Oversize), Folder 226)
        - Q-VU Gazette, 1993 August 7 (Box 38 (Oversize), Folder 227)
        - Sawyer's Inc., View-Master Reel Lists (Box 38 (Oversize), Folder 228)
        - Uncut sheets with chromolithograph stereographs, circa 1900 (Box 38 (Oversize), Folder 229)
    - Photograph Button Literature
      Related Archival Materials note
      Associated Materials: Photograph buttons can be found in Series VI. Realia with Photographs.
      - Art Medallion Co. (Box 39, Folder 230)
      - Brizee, Marjorie, Letter to Palmquist about Photo Button Plaques (Box 39, Folder 231)
      - Cruver Manufacturing Co., Letter to Chester Kilzer, 1935 February 4 (Box 39, Folder 232)
      - Cruver Manufacturing Co., Advertisements for Novelties (Box 39, Folder 233)
      - Cruver Manufacturing Co., Order Blank and Envelope (Box 39, Folder 234)
      - Cruver Manufacturing Co., Advertisement for Panel Portrait Salesmen (Box 39, Folder 235)
      - Cruver Manufacturing Co., Sales Cases (Box 39, Folder 236)
      - Cruver Manufacturing Co., Wholesale Price Lists (Box 39, Folder 237)
      - Cruver Manufacturing Co., Photo Button Chart No. 1-14 (Box 39, Folder 238-251)
      - Cruver Manufacturing Co., Photo Button Background Chart (Box 39, Folder 252)
      - Cruver Manufacturing Co., Photo Button Chart Nos. 1-6, 8-11 (Box 40, Folder 253-262)
    - Advertising for Photographic Novelties
      - Derick Studio, Viz-Eclipse, 1932 (Box 41, Folder 263)
      - F. H. Noble & Co., Button Machines, Button Frames, Button Parts, 1901 December (Box 41, Folder 264)
      - Franklin Putnam, Photographic Outfits, circa 1888 (Box 41, Folder 265)
      - Kodak, Photographic Sensitizer for Cloth and Paper (Box 41, Folder 266)
      - Kug-Art Photo Service, Photo Novelty Mirrors (Box 41, Folder 267)
      - Milburn Manufacturing Co., Multiplying Slides, 1902 August (Box 41, Folder 268)
      - Nashau Pillow Co., Photographic Blue Prints, 1900 (Box 41, Folder 269)
      - Parisian Novelty Co., Photo Jewelry and Buttons, 1901 February (Box 41, Folder 270)
      - Photo Jewelry Manufacturing Co., Photo Jewelry and Buttons (Box 41, Folder 271)
      - Ritz, Photographs on Linen, 1964 April (Box 41, Folder 272)
      - Sprague-Hathaway Studios, Miniatures on Ivory and Porcelain (Box 41, Folder 273)
    - Photographic Product Literature and Instruction Sheets
      - Actien Gesellschaft für Anilin-fabrikation, Rodinal (Box 42, Folder 274)
      - Afga Ansco Corporation, Rodinal (Box 42, Folder 275)
      - Altura Photo Paper Co., Iris Paper (Box 42, Folder 276)
      - Ansco, Film and Color Film (Box 42, Folder 277)
      - Anthony and Scovill Company, List of Products (Box 42, Folder 278)
      - Art Album Co., Metal Back Album (Box 42, Folder 279)
      - Blair Camera Co., Advertisement (Box 42, Folder 280)
      - Burke and James, Soline (Box 42, Folder 281)
      - Burroughs Wellcome and Company, Hazeline Cream (Box 42, Folder 282)
      - Chemical Supply Co., Formula Number 16 (Box 42, Folder 283)
      - Cyko, Cyko Paper (Box 42, Folder 284)
      - Defender Photo Supply Company, Velour Black, Vulcan Film, Chromatone Photo Paper, etc. (Box 42, Folder 285)
      - Eastman Kodak Co., Panchromatic Film, Velox Paper, Azo Paper, Aristo Toner, etc. (Box 42, Folder 286)
      - Fink-Roselieve Co., Formula 33 Thermolecular Fine Grain Developer (Box 42, Folder 287)
      - Forbes Photographic Plates (Box 42, Folder 288)
      - G. Cramer Dry Plate Company (Box 42, Folder 289)
      - Gennert, G., List of Camera supplies, etc. (Box 42, Folder 290)
      - George Murphy, Foreground Graded Filter (Box 42, Folder 291)
      - Harrison and Harrison, Filters (Box 42, Folder 292)
      - Hauf Aktiengesellschaft, Methylparamidophenol (Box 42, Folder 293)
      - Ica, Exposure Time Tables (Box 42, Folder 294)
      - Identification Corporation of America, Camera Registration (Box 42, Folder 295)
      - Ilotype Company, Matt-Surface ILO (Box 42, Folder 296)
      - Ingilis & Co., Sepia Bromides (Box 42, Folder 297)
      - J. G. Burns Manufacturing Company, Mirrorgraphic Mantels (Box 42, Folder 298)
      - John Carbutt, Lantern Transparencies (Box 42, Folder 299)
      - Keuffel and Esser Company, Blue Printing (Box 42, Folder 300)
      - Kilborn Photo Paper Company, Sepia Development, Kruxo Sodas (Box 42, Folder 301)
      - M. A. Seed Dry Plate Company, Seed Plates (Box 42, Folder 302)
      - Mon-Blanc Chemical Company, Von-L Developer (Box 42, Folder 303)
      - Photowerke, Color Slide Film (Box 42, Folder 304)
      - Robert Dempster Company, Dry Plates (Box 42, Folder 305)
      - Rotograph, Photo Paper (Box 42, Folder 306)
      - Sears, Roebuck and Company, Darko Paper (Box 42, Folder 307)
      - Standard Dry Plate Company, Plates and Developing Formula (Box 42, Folder 308)
      - Stanley Dry Plate (Box 42, Folder 309)
      - Sun Ray Photo Co., Enlarger (Box 42, Folder 310)
      - Worcester Envelope Company, Rice Bond Enclosures (Box 42, Folder 311)
      - Multiple Manufacturers, Plates, Exposure Meters, etc. (Box 42, Folder 312)
      - Unidentified author, Recipes for Collodion (Box 42, Folder 313-314)
- Photographic Processing Material, circa 1875-circa 1993; Series III; 7.3; (13 boxes)
  Series III is organized into nine subseries: Photograph Exposure Logs, Photographers' Studio Envelopes, Photographic Print Finishing Envelopes, Photographers' Stationery, Photographic Equipment, Photographic Processing Material, Printing Masks, Photographic Negatives, and Photographic Paper.
  This series consists of material that documents aspects of treating photographic film and paper after its exposure to produce a negative or positive image.
  The series includes material used by photographers in their workflows to process and distribute photographic material, including logs used to record photographic exposures and envelopes used by commercial and amateur photographers, as well as stationery used by commercial photographers.
  The series also includes photographic equipment used in processing photographs, as well as boxes and envelopes used to market photographic negatives and paper to photographers.
  - Photograph Exposure Logs
    This subseries consists of used and unused photograph exposure logs marketed to amateur photographers.
    - E. & H. T. Anthony, Note Book of Photography for the Use of Landscape Photographers; log entries by Frederick Montgomery Livingston (born 1873), Brooklyn, New York, 1893-1903 (Box 43, Folder 315)
    - Burroughs Wellcome & Co., Wellcome's Photographic Exposure Record and Diary, 1909 (Box 43, Folder 316)
    - Burroughs Wellcome & Co., Wellcome's Photographic Exposure Record and Diary, 1915 (Box 43, Folder 317)
    - Burroughs Wellcome & Co., Wellcome's Photographic Exposure Calculator Handbook and Diary, 1936 (Box 43, Folder 318)
    - General Electric Company, Photo Data Book, 1946 (Box 43, Folder 319)
    - Harrison & Harrison Optical Engineers, Harrison's Color Film Exposure Record, circa 1946 (Box 43, Folder 320)
  - Photographers' Studio Envelopes
    This subseries consists of photographers' studio envelopes used by commercial photographers to deliver photographic prints to their customers.
    - Apeda Studio, New York, New York, 1906-1990 (Box 44, Folder 321)
    - Beckford Photo Studio, Boston, Massachusetts, circa 1888 (Box 44, Folder 322)
    - Brown, C. E., Chelsea, Massachusetts (Box 44, Folder 323)
    - Brown, G. P., Beverly, Massachusetts (Box 44, Folder 324)
    - C. W. Parker and Co., Seattle, Washington (Box 44, Folder 325)
    - Chickering, Elmer, Boston, Massachusetts (Box 44, Folder 326)
      Includes proofs
    - Davis and Howard, Boston, Massachusetts (Box 44, Folder 327)
    - Doremus, L.H., Paterson, New Jersey (Box 44, Folder 328)
    - Frye, Philip K., Portland, Maine (Box 44, Folder 329)
    - Gilmore, M.G., Oldtown, Maine (Box 44, Folder 330)
    - J. E. Purdy and Co., Boston, Massachusetts, circa 1912 (Box 44, Folder 331)
    - Pach Bros., New York, New York (Box 44, Folder 332)
    - Unique Portrait Co., Portland, Oregon (Box 44, Folder 333)
    - Young, S., New York, New York (Box 44, Folder 334)
  - Photographic Print Finishing Envelopes
    This subseries includes envelopes used by amateur photographers to hold film for processing by commercial photographers or by photographic print finishing firms, which often marketed their services through drugstores.
    - Andrew J. Lloyd Co., Boston, Massachusetts (Box 45, Folder 335)
    - Associated Photo Co., Cincinnati, Ohio (Box 45, Folder 336)
    - Baldwin-Gruber, Los Angeles, California (Box 45, Folder 337)
    - Barnard Studio, Wallace, Idaho (Box 45, Folder 338)
    - Blakely Photo Finishing, Hollywood, California (Box 45, Folder 339)
    - Boulevard Pharmacy, San Francisco, California (Box 45, Folder 340)
    - Bowman Drug Co., Oakland, California (Box 45, Folder 341)
    - The Boys, Girard, Kansas (Box 45, Folder 342)
    - Camera Shop, New Haven, Connecticut (Box 45, Folder 343)
    - Caples Camera Co., Tucson, Arizona (Box 45, Folder 344)
    - Cinema Art Studio, Hollywood, California (Box 45, Folder 345)
    - Corinne Gift Shop, Los Angeles, California (Box 45, Folder 346)
    - Darling Studio, Ashland, Oregon (Box 45, Folder 347)
    - Dearing Photo Service, Bloomfield, New Jersey (Box 45, Folder 348)
    - Dinham & Sons, Torquay, England (Box 45, Folder 349)
    - Eastman Kodak, Rochester, New York (Box 45, Folder 350)
    - Elko Photo Finishing Co. (Box 45, Folder 351)
    - Foto Corso, Vienna, Austria (Box 45, Folder 352)
    - Fox Movie Flash, San Francisco, California (Box 45, Folder 353)
    - Free Developing Company, Kansas City, Missouri (Box 45, Folder 354)
    - Glo-Tone, James, Louisiana (Box 45, Folder 355)
    - Golling & Heese, Minneapolis, Minnesota (Box 45, Folder 356)
    - Hale's Drug, Reno, Nevada, circa 1962 (Box 45, Folder 357)
    - Harvey & Lewis Co., multiple Connecticut and Massachusetts locations (Box 45, Folder 358)
    - Hollymount Drugs, Los Angeles, California (Box 45, Folder 359)
    - J. Lizars, Edinburgh, Scotland (Box 45, Folder 360)
    - Jack Rabbit Co., Spartanburg, South Carolina (Box 45, Folder 361)
    - Jacobs Pharmacy Co., Atlanta, Georgia (Box 45, Folder 362)
    - Joe M. Sejhar, Hot Springs, Arkansas (Box 45, Folder 363)
    - Jones Drug, Tucson, Arizona, circa 1962 (Box 45, Folder 364)
    - Knowlton Drug Store, Coquille, Oregon, circa 1921 (Box 45, Folder 365)
    - Kodakery, Portland, Oregon (Box 45, Folder 366)
    - Kodalux, Palo Alto, California, circa 1993 (Box 45, Folder 367)
    - Lane Drug Stores, Atlanta, Georgia (Box 45, Folder 368)
    - Leslie's Studio, Manchester, New Hampshire (Box 45, Folder 369)
    - Lowman & Hanford Co., Seattle, Washington (Box 45, Folder 370)
    - Lyle & Gaston, Atlanta, Georgia (Box 45, Folder 371)
    - Mail-a-Way Service Co., San Francisco, California, circa 1961 (Box 45, Folder 372)
    - Marter's (Box 45, Folder 373)
    - Midwest Photo Service, Grand Junction, Colorado, circa 1945 (Box 45, Folder 374)
    - Munn's, Atlanta, Georgia (Box 45, Folder 375)
    - Myhre Studio, Luverne, Minnesota (Box 45, Folder 376)
    - Newman Drug Co., Los Angeles, California (Box 45, Folder 377)
    - Photo-Craft, Canton, Ohio, circa 1940 (Box 45, Folder 378)
    - Ray's Photo Service, La Crosse, Wisconsin (Box 45, Folder 379)
    - Rochester Laboratory, Rochester, New York (Box 45, Folder 380)
    - Skyland Studio, Asheville, North Carolina (Box 45, Folder 381)
    - Star Photo, Atlanta, Georgia (Box 45, Folder 382)
    - Studer Photo Co., San Antonio, Texas (Box 45, Folder 383)
    - Sun Photo Service, Los Angeles, California (Box 45, Folder 384)
    - Thomas Drug Co., Los Angeles, California, circa 1931 (Box 45, Folder 385)
    - Thrifty Drug Store, California (Box 45, Folder 386)
    - United Film Club, Inc., Los Angeles, California (Box 45, Folder 387)
    - Walgreens Drug Store, Tucson, Arizona, circa 1964-1965 (Box 45, Folder 388)
    - Walgreens, 1994 (Box 45, Folder 389)
    - Wayne's Photofinishing (Box 45, Folder 390)
    - Wright's, Kansas City, Missouri (Box 45, Folder 391)
    - Unidentified firms (Box 45, Folder 392)
  - Photographers' Stationery
    This subseries consists of stationery, bills of sale, and illustrated letterheads used by commercial photographers in their businesses.
    - Art Photo Studio, Peking, China, 1941 March 5 (Box 46, Folder 393)
    - Ayres, George B. Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1899 June 1 (Box 46, Folder 394)
    - Bass Camera Co., Chicago, Illinois, 1969 July 25 (Box 46, Folder 395)
    - Burke & James, Inc., Chicago, Illinois, 1916 July 25 (Box 46, Folder 396)
    - Davies, W. J., Bozeman, Montana, 1894 November 30 (Box 46, Folder 397)
    - Dutro, Daniel, Havre, Montana, 1895 December 2 (Box 46, Folder 398)
    - Erikson, Augusta, Montana, 1897 July 11 (Box 46, Folder 399)
    - Fullerton, R. W., Great Falls, Montana, 1894-1896 (Box 46, Folder 400)
    - Hageman, E. O., Hamilton, Montana, 1896 March 12 (Box 46, Folder 401)
    - Horgan, Robey & Co., Boston, Massachusetts, 1895 September 20 (Box 46, Folder 402)
    - Hussey, Lewiston, Maine, circa 1885 (Box 46, Folder 403)
    - Ingalls, Frank M., Missoula, Montana, 1894 August 27 (Box 46, Folder 404)
    - K. T. Thompson Photo Studio, Peping, China, 1941 May 28 (Box 46, Folder 405)
    - Kupper, L. V., Edinboro, Pennsylvania, 1897 March 26 (Box 46, Folder 406)
    - Photo Sosna, Heidelberg, Germany, 1953 August 28 (Box 46, Folder 407)
    - Potter, George W., Livingston, Montana, 1896-1897 (Box 46, Folder 408)
    - Providence Photographic Depot, Providence, Rhode Island, 1895 August-September (Box 46, Folder 409)
    - Reed, C. O., Philipsburg, Montana, 1894 October 4 (Box 46, Folder 410)
    - Rice & Koehler, Great Falls, Montana, 1894 August 3 (Box 46, Folder 411)
    - Sprague & Hathaway Co., West Somerville, Massachusetts, 1895 June 29 (Box 46, Folder 412)
    - U.S.A. School Aerial Photography, Rochester, New York, 1918 November 22 (Box 46, Folder 413)
  - Photographic Equipment
    This subseries consists of equipment used by photographers in creating photographs.
    - Leather carrying case for a field camera, circa 1900 (Box 47, Folder 414)
    - H. C. White Company, Radioptican postcard projector, circa 1910 (Box 48)
    - Eastman Kodak Company, Filter test chart, circa 1935 (Box 49, Folder 415)
    - C. J. Bubla, Inc., Lens tissue, circa 1945 (Box 49, Folder 416)
    - Weston Electrical Instruments Corporation, The Weston System of emulsion ratings, 1946 (Box 49, Folder 417)
    - Leitz Rondinax 35, Daylight developing tank, circa 1954-1962 (Box 50, Folder 418)
    - Eastman Kodak Company, Exposure computer for Kodak PolyContrast Filters, 1964 (Box 49, Folder 419)
    - Wallace Photo Products, Wallace aperture guide, 1983 (Box 49, Folder 420)
  - Photographic Processing Material
    This subseries includes material used by photographers to process photographs including retouching negatives and preparing photographic prints and transparencies
    - H. L. Roberts & Co., Gihon's Opaque, circa 1875 (Box 51, Folder 421)
      Gihon's Opaque is a reddish pigment invented by John Lawrence Gihon (1839-1878), which photographers applied to negatives to block out light during processing
    - Eastman Kodak Company, Velox transparent watercolor stamp outfit, circa 1910-circa 1920 (Box 51, Folder 422)
    - Dennison Manufacturing Company, Lantern slide binding, circa 1920 (Box 51, Folder 423)
    - Eastman Kodak Company, Kodak dry mounting tissue, circa 1920 (Box 51, Folder 424)
    - Engel Manufacturing Company, Art Corners, 1924-1926 (Box 51, Folder 425)
    - Keystone View Company, Lantern slide crayons, circa 1935 (Box 51, Folder 426)